我们一直在关注不可变对象的质量
We've been focusing on quality of immutable objects
到目前为止的阅读。
so far in this reading.
可变数据类型呢？
What about mutable data types?
现在回想一下我们的定义。
Now recall our definition.
两个物体不能区分时是相等的
Two objects are equal when they cannot be distinguished
通过观察。
by observation.
对于可变对象，现在有两种解释方法。
With mutable objects, there are now two ways to interpret this.
也许他们——我们所说的通过观察来区分
Maybe they-- what we mean by distinguished by observation
是不能用观察来区分的
is that they can't be distinguished by observation
这不会改变对象的状态。
that doesn't change the state of the objects.
换言之，它们无法区分
In other words, they can't be distinguished
如果只调用observer、producer和creator方法。
if you only call observer, producer, and creator methods.
这通常被称为观察平等，
This is often called observational equality,
因为它在测试两个对象是否
because it's testing whether two objects look
在程序的当前状态下也是如此，
the same in the current state of the program,
不改变状态。
without changing the state.
更有力的说法是
A stronger way of saying it is that they
任何观察都无法区分，甚至
can't be distinguished by any observation, even
状态更改。
state changes.
这个解释允许调用
And this interpretation allows calling any methods on the two
对象，包括变换器。
objects, including mutators.
这通常被称为行为平等，
This is often called behavioral equality,
因为它测试两个对象的行为是否相同
since it tests whether two objects will behave the same
在这个和所有未来的国家。
in this and all future states.
现在对于没有变异的不可变对象，
Now for immutable objects which don't have mutators,
观察和行为上的平等是一样的。
observational and behavioral equality are identical.
对于可变对象，它可以是
For mutable objects, it can be very
试图实施严格的观察平等，
tempting to implement strict observational equality,
换句话说，忽略变异。
in other words, ignoring mutators.
Java实际上使用了观察等式
Java actually uses observational equality
对于它的大多数可变数据类型。
for most of its mutable data types.
如果两个不同的列表对象包含相同的序列
If two distinct list objects contain the same sequence
元素的，然后等于它们相等的报告，
of elements, then equals reports that they are equal,
即使突变者会发现它们是不同的。
even though a mutator would find that they are different.
但是使用观测相等可能会导致微小的错误。
But using observational equality can lead to subtle bugs.
事实上，它让我们很容易打破
In fact, it allows us to easily break
其他集合数据结构的表示不变量。
the rep invariants of other collection data structures.
这里有一个例子。
Here's an example.
假设我们制作一个列表，在其中添加一个元素，
Suppose we make a list, add an element to it,
然后我们把它放进一套。
and then we put it into a set.
所以我们现在有一组字符串列表。
So we have now a set of lists of strings.
我们将把这个列表添加到这个集合中。
And we're going to add this list to that set.
现在我们可以问一下，这套有没有
Now we can ask, does this set contain
我们刚放进去的名单？
the list we just put into it?
是的，答案是肯定的。
And yes, the answer is yes.
现在假设我们改变了列表。
Now suppose we mutate the list.
所以它以前只有一个。
So it used to have just A in it.
我们现在在结尾处加上了再见。
We've now added goodbye to the ends.
所以名单上有一个和再见。
So the list has A and goodbye.
现在我们要问的是，这个集合包含这个列表吗？
Now we ask, does this set contain this list?
答案是错误的。
The answer is false.
但比这更糟，因为当
But it's worse than that, because when
我们迭代集合的成员，
we iterate over members of the set,
我们还在里面找到名单。
we still find the list in there.
但是contains说它不在那里。
But contains says it's not there.
看看这个。
So look at this.
所以我们在列表中迭代
So we are iterating over the lists
在这个集合中找到的。
that are found in this set.
所以我要对每个列表的值
So L is going to take on the value of each list that
在这个集合中找到。
is found in this set.
我们要从名单中找出一个L——从那一组中，
We're going to get an L out of that list-- out of that set,
我很抱歉。
I'm sorry.
然后我们要这个
And then we're going to ask for this L
我们刚在片场找到的。
that we have just found in the set.
它来自集合的迭代。
It's coming out of the iteration of the set.
这套衣服里有L吗？
Does the set contain that L?
答案是不。
The answer is no.
这显然违背了我们所期望的含意，
This clearly violates what we expect contains to mean,
以及我们所期望的迭代意味着什么。
and what we expect iteration to mean.
他们现在不同意元素是否在集合中。
They disagree now about whether an element is in the set.
这套显然坏了。
The set is clearly broken.
如果转到联机Python，您可以看到这段代码正在运行
You can see this code in action if you go to the online Python
带着那个链接做家教。
tutor with that link.
怎么回事？
So what's going on?
好吧，字符串列表是一个可变对象。
Well, a list of string is a mutable object.
在标准Java实现中
In the standard Java implementation
像列表、突变这样的集合类
of collection classes like list, mutations
影响equals和hashcode的结果。
affect the result of equals and hashcode.
当列表第一次放入哈希集中时，
When the list is first put into the hash set,
它存储在相应的散列桶中
it's stored in the hash bucket corresponding
对于当时的hashcode结果，
to its hashcode result at that time,
它只使用元素A。
which uses only the element A.
当列表随后发生变异时
When the list is subsequently mutated
所以它有一个和再见，它的哈希码变化。
so that it has A and goodbye on it, it's hashcode changes.
但hashset并不知道这一点。
But hashset doesn't know about that.
它没有意识到它需要被转移到另一个桶里。
It doesn't realize it needs to be moved to a different bucket.
所以当容器去寻找它时，它永远找不到它。
So when contains goes and looks for it, it can never find it.
另一方面，迭代器没有
The iterator, on the other hand, doesn't
遭受那个问题的折磨。
suffer from that problem.
只是一次一个地检查散列桶
It's just going through the hash buckets one at a time
也不想用它的hashcode查找任何东西。
and not actually trying to look anything up using its hashcode.
所以当equals和hashcode可能受到变异的影响时，
So when equals and hashcode can be affected by mutation,
我们可以打破哈希表的rep不变量
we can break the rep invariant of a hash table that
使用该对象作为键。
uses that object as a key.
这里有一个非常有说服力的引用
Here's a very telling quote from the specification
在Java.util.set中。
of Java.util.set.
“如果可变对象是
"Great care must be exercised if mutable objects are
用作集合元素。
used as set elements.
未指定集合的行为
Behavior of a set is not specified
如果对象的值被更改
if the value of an object is changed
当对象是
in a manner that affects equals comparisons while the object is
集合中的元素。“
an element in the set."
不幸的是，Java库是，
The Java library is, unfortunately,
解释方式不一致
inconsistent about the way it interprets
对于可变类等于。
equals for mutable classes.
集合使用观察等式，
Collections use observational equality,
但是其他可变类，比如stringbuilder，
but other mutable classes, like stringbuilder,
使用行为平等。
use behavioral equality.
我们应该从这个例子中吸取教训
The lesson we should draw from this example
是为了防止虫子，等于
is that to be safe from bugs, equals
应实现行为平等。
should implement behavioral equality.
这意味着两个引用应该等于
That means two references should be equals if
只有当它们是同一对象的别名时。
and only if they are aliases for the same object.
所以可变对象应该继承hashcode中的equals
So mutable objects should just inherit equals in the hashcode
直接从物体上，因为
directly from object, because that's
它已经实现了什么。
what it already implements.
对于需要观察平等概念的客户，
For clients that need a notion of observational equality,
两个对象在当前状态下看起来相同，
where the two objects look the same in the current state,
最好定义一个全新的方法
it's better to define a completely new method that
不会影响平等的方式，
won't interfere with the way equals,
hashcode和hash表的行为。
and hashcode, and hash tables behave.
例如，我们可以称之为类似的。
We might call it, for example, similar.
这里是equals和hashcode的最终规则
So here is the final rule for equals and hashcode
对于抽象数据类型。
for abstract data types.
如果你在写一个不可变的数据类型，
If you're writing an immutable data type,
那么你的等号应该比较抽象值。
then your equals should compare abstract values.
等于说平等者应该
It's the same as saying that equals should
提供行为平等。
provide behavioral equality.
hashcode应该将抽象值映射为整数。
And hashcode should map the abstract value to an integer.
所以不可变类型必须同时重写equals和hashcode。
So immutable types must override both equals and hashcode.
对于可变类型，equals应该比较引用，
For mutable types, equals should compare references,
就像平等一样。
just like equals equals does.
这和说平等一样
This is the same as saying equals
应该提供行为上的平等，但也有参考价值
should provide behavioral equality, but also referential
平等。
equality.
hashcode应该将引用映射为整数。
And hashcode should map the reference into an integer.
所以可变类型不应该重写equals和hashcode
So mutable types should not override equals and hashcode
完全。
at all.
它应该只使用默认值和限制
It should simply use the default and limitations
由对象提供。
provided by object.
Java的集合不遵循这个规则，
Java doesn't follow this rule for its collections,
不幸的是，这导致了我们在上面看到的陷阱。
unfortunately, which leads to the pitfalls that we saw above.